<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text analysis on Natrium Theme</title>
    <link>/tags/text-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text analysis on Natrium Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 15:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/text-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Semantic fingerprinting&#39; 10-K business descriptions</title>
      <link>/semantic-fingerprinting-10-k-business-descriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/semantic-fingerprinting-10-k-business-descriptions/</guid>
      <description>For me, one of the most interesting areas of data analytics is in processing text as data. Because texts are created by humans, they tend to be difficult to interpret, biased, error-prone and idiosyncratic. This is exactly what makes text interesting as a source of data. In the past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project that involves analyzing annual reports of U.S. firms. After scraping the 10-K reports from the SEC website (using this R package), we extract the business description section of each report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Guardian News Articles Using Naive Bayes</title>
      <link>/classifying-guardian-news-articles-using-naive-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/classifying-guardian-news-articles-using-naive-bayes/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I adapted the Naive Bayes model used in this excellent video to classify text documents in Python. Classifying text documents is a fairly straightforward task which is fun to do, and so I wanted to test it out by classifying articles from the Guardian belonging to four categories. In the rest of this post, I’m going to outline some theory on probabilities and Bayes’ Law. Then, we’ll pre-process the Guardian news articles and attempt to classify as many of them to the correct section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>